# 佛山·顺德
Shunde, Foshan
# 看到没 我后面挂的这4只烧鹅
See? The four roast geese behind me.
# 还有旁边的 一条条的叉烧
Next to them, strings of barbecue pork.
# 它们不仅颜色好看 外皮红亮
Not only are they eye appealing, shiny red,
# 而且还流着汤汁
but also the juice is dripping down.
# 太诱人了！
It’s really seducing!
# 我们现在在大头华烧鹅店
We are now in “Da Tou Hua Roast Geese Restaurant”
# 这不是传说当中的菜单吗
Isn’t it the menu in the legend?
# 烧鹅 每只480元
Roast Geese, 480 RMB each
# 半只240元
240 RMB for half
# 还可以选叉烧拼鹅肝
You can also choose to have barbecue pork goose liver combo.
# 也分大中小份
And there are also large, medium and small portion
# 还有鹅杂三拼
There’s also goose trio.
# 真的 鹅的全身都是宝 一样都跑不了
The geese are really stuffed with treasure, everything.
# 想吃哪一种
Which one do you want?
# 可以带你过去
I can show you
# 看一下制作炉
to have a look at the oven.
# 可以看
Can I?
Sure
# 哇 还有鹅
Wa! There are geese too.
# 这个是等一下 要去被风干的鹅
These geese are to be dried.
# 等一下我给你看
Let me show you later.
# 这个鹅又上来了（被拎上来）
The geese are coming up (being taken up)
# 我们自己做的
We made them ourselves,
# 没有色素
without any colouring
# 我们现在（下来看一下）
We now (come down and have a look)
# 大瓦缸
It’s simple, this is a big porcelain tank.
# 过来看 拍这个鹅
Come on! Film them, the geese.
# 拍一下
Film them
# 这么肥的鹅
The geese are really fat.
# 处理好的鹅 放在炉子里烤干些水分
The processed geese are parched in the oven.
# 在鹅的皮上 洒脆皮卤水
On the skin of the geese, we spray some crispy master stock.
# 等一下 冷气风干
Then, we will dry them with the air-conditioner,
# 再进炉子里烤
Before they’re roasted in the oven.
# 这个没有色素的
It’s free of any colouring.
# 叔叔 这只鹅得多少斤
Uncle, how heavy is such a goose?
# 这一只鹅多少斤
How heavy is this goose?
# 八九斤
Eight or nine “jin” (1 “jin” = 500 grams)
# 每一只鹅都气鼓鼓的
The geese look flattened.
# 跟着我过去 风干鹅
Follow me. We’re going to dry the goose.
# 小心 小心
Watch you step.
# 小心
Be careful.
# 现在我们要跟着叔叔
We need to follow the uncle,
to have a look
# 鹅被风干的情景
how the geese are dried
# 哇
Wow!
# 每到一个制作场景 都是一声 哇 的赞叹
Every step is so amazing and is worth a big “Wow”.
# 来 我们看一看 鹅被风干是什么样的情景呢
Come! Let’s take a look and see the geese being dried.
# 上面这个冷气
The air-conditioner is up there.
# 有专门的设施
It’s specially designed.
# 我们是自己研发出来的（这种做法）
We figured out (this method) on our own.
# 冷气风干
Drying with air-conditioner.
# 一般烧鹅如果没有进行风干处理的话
If the geese are not dried before being roasted
# 猜测意思：再出去 外面温度35度 36度
(I guess he means) And then you go out. It’s 35 or 36 degrees outside.
# 我这里零下2度 这个不一样的
Here, it’s -2 degrees. It’s completely different.
# 如果这样搞（进行风干处理）呢
Our method (to dry)
# 有什么好处
has the advantage.
# 出去外面 温度都很高
The temperature is really high outside.
# 你却把这个鹅皮搞干了
But you dry the skin of the geese.
# 里面的肉就变了
The meat may be rotten.
# 所以 我们用这个冷气风干
That’s why we dry with the air-conditioner.
# 这样 鹅烧出来皮好吃一点
Then the roast geese will have a more tasty skin.
# 就是口感会更好
The texture is much better
# 肯定的
Certainly
# 你看一下
Take a look!
# 你摸一下这个皮
Feel the skin
# 它这边有点光滑
It’s quite smooth here.
# 烧出来这个皮就很脆了
It would become really crispy after roasting.
# 所以 风干后做出来口感会比较好
So the texture is much better if it’s dried first.
# 一般做烧鹅 没有这个流程
Other roast geese do not go through this step.
# 没有这个流程的话 皮可能就没有那么脆
The skin won’t be that crispy without this stel.
# 懂了吗 这个风干就是为了让鹅皮更脆一些
Got it? Drying it is for a more crispy skin.
# 烤出来的口感会不同
The texture is completely different
# 顺德 有60个招牌菜
There are 60 signature dishes in Shunde.
# 我们进两个
We have two
# 一个大头华烧鹅
One is “Da Tou Hua oast geese”.
# 一个腊肉蒸鲮鱼干
The other one is “cured pork steamed with dried catfish”
# 现在在上面 应该有北风 有太阳
It should be up there. There’s northern wind, and sun.
# 气候条件会好一些
The weather should contribute a lot.
# 哇 有这么多
Wa! There’s a lot
# 500多条鱼
More than half a thousand fish
# 叔叔 这个鱼得晒多久
Uncle, how long does it take to dry the fish?
# 今天可以了
They’re done today.
# 这个鱼可以了
They’re done now.
# 颜色是比较深的
It has a darker colour.
# 今天就可以收了
We can get them back today
# 第一次感觉 鱼干像风铃一样
It’s the first time that I feel the dried fish is similar to wind chimes.
# 今天来的正巧
Today is a really good timing.
# 这些鱼 都风干好了
The fish are dried now.
# 接下来 叔叔要把它从楼上
Next, uncle needs to take the fish from upstairs,
# 直接是这么弄下去
all the way down.
# 怎么弄的呢 看一看
Let’s see how it can be done.
# 风干后的鹅进烤炉
Put the goose into the oven after drying.
# 一个小时 可以出炉
They will be ready in an hour.
# 用瓦缸做烧鹅的方法 得几百年了
The method of using a porcelain tank is centuries old.
# 它是最传统 最古老的做烧鹅的方式
It’s the most traditional way of making roast duck.
# 因为这个炉子 有一些优点
As the oven has its own strengths.
# 保温
It keeps the moisture.
# 烧出来的效果
很香
The aroma of the product is exceptional.
# 和不锈钢的缸烧出来的不同
It’s significantly different from the products of a stainless steel oven.
# 含有传统 古老的味道
The difference is the traditional, nostalgic taste.
# 鹅已经就位了
The geese are not ready.
# 得烤差不多一个小时
It takes almost an hour,
# 才能看到颜色好看的烧鹅
To have the geese with appealing colour.
# 叔叔 每天的工作就是提着鹅到处跑
Uncle! So your job is taking the geese here and there every day?
# 这个最厉害 这都是鹅肉原汁
This is the most attractive one, the juice from the goose.
# 刚刚出炉的好吃
The tastes the best when it just comes out from the oven.
# 好 谢谢
Good! Thanks.
# 鹅皮和鹅肉 都要分离开
The skin and the meat are separated.
# 颜色是很好看 是枣红色的
The colour is really nice. It’s dark red.
# 刚才叔叔也说了嘛
As the uncle has just said,
# 在做的过程中 鹅需要进行风干处理
the geese need to the dried.
# 目的呢 是为了让皮更脆一些
The purpose is to have a more crispy skin.
# 咱们看一看 皮是不是很脆呢
Let’s see if it’s really that crispy.
# 能听到吗
Can you hear it?
# 它这种脆 就像纸一样的脆感
The crispiness, is like a piece of paper.
# 真的是 皮脆 肉嫩 多汁
It’s really, crispy outside and juicy inside.
# 还有呢 如果觉得腻
And, if you feel greesy,
# 配酸甜口的梅子酱就很不错
The sweet and sour plum sauce is a perfect match.
# 不要忘了 我们还有鹅肝拼盘
Don’t forget that we have a goose liver combo
# 这个蜜汁叉烧
This honey barbecue pork.
# 真的会有迷一般的魅力
is really seducing.
# 吃起来特别润滑
It’s really smooth.
# 鹅肝呢 就是绵软 细腻
And the goose liver is tender and rich.
# 味道呢 会比较淡一些
The tastes is a bit more mild.
# 鹅肠 就是更加爽脆
And the goose intestines are exceptionally crunchy.
# 咱们这次是花了160块钱
This time we have spent 160 RMB.
# 烧鹅（四分之一）还有鹅肝是自己买的
The (quarter of) roast goose and the goose liver are paid by ourselves.
# 叉烧是送的
The barbecue pork is complementary.
# 好一桌的味觉体验
What a table of experience of taste.
# 刚才老板把鱼从上面放下来
The boss has just brought the fish down here.
# 在这儿晾着
And put them all here.
# 也不怕鱼被猫偷走吗
Wouldn’t they be stolen by cats?